<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>jhbraun</title>
 <link href="http://jordanhbraun.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://jordanhbraun.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2014-11-20T15:51:57-06:00</updated>
 <id>http://jordanhbraun.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jordan H Braun</name>
   <email>jordan@greatjob.is</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Design Science</title>
   <link href="http://jordanhbraun.github.io//2014/11/20/Design-Science/"/>
   <updated>2014-11-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://jordanhbraun.github.io/2014/11/20/Design-Science</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are designers, not artists.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we want to be great designers we need to start behaving more like scientists and less like artists. Design is not applied art; design is the science of problem solving. This is not an expression of our own thoughts, we are creating real solutions for real people.We are trying to solve problems for real people. We are not working in a closed studio in anticipation of a gallery opening. Testing isn’t part of the process; testing is the process. We need to be design scientists.
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientists know what’s up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a lot of lessons to learn from scientists. Their process and their mindset suits our goals well. Their process is continuous and cyclical, just like that word that we like to throw around: iterative. They embrace failure. This is just a buzz phrase in the design and startup world, but its reality for scientists. In the world of science, failure is every bit as important as success, as long as learning is happening. Scientists don’t design experiments stacked to succeed, they design experiments to isolate variables and learn. I&amp;#39;ve seen plenty of user tests designed to prove the hypotheses, this is bad design. Validation needs to go both ways, or you’re just wasting time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we want to be design scientists, and we acknowledge that testing is our process, then what does that process look like? The scientific method, of course!
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part is up to you. Get out there and observe some people. Evaluate your product. Do some daydreaming. Discover your design problem.
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypothesis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brainstorm your heart out. This is the fun part. A lot of people make the mistake of stopping here, or going straight to build after brainstorming. These are assumptions that need validated.
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build whatever you need to build and put it in front of people! Don’t build more than you have to, we just want to validate our assumptions as quickly as possible, so that we can make another run through this cycle. Keep your build focused on the test. 
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s time to evaluate what you’ve learned. Did the experiment hit its success criteria? Why or why not? New questions should be arising, which leads us back to our first step: the formulation of a question.
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing takes you where you need to be&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole process is the test. It is a cycle of learning and constant improvement. It is not something you do before or after a build. The build is something you do to support the test that leads us closer to our goal: better solutions. If you’re just testing at the beginning or the end of a build then your process is not a science. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>An Open Letter to Barack Obama</title>
   <link href="http://jordanhbraun.github.io//2014/08/17/An-open-letter-to-Barack-Obama/"/>
   <updated>2014-08-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://jordanhbraun.github.io/2014/08/17/An-open-letter-to-Barack-Obama</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;President Obama,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could go down in history as this nation&amp;#39;s most disappointing president. Your campaign inspired the people of the United States, young and old, but you have not delivered. When we voted for &amp;quot;change&amp;quot; we did not mean &amp;quot;change your mind.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have about 2 years left in your term, here is a list of items I have prepared that could help you save face. You do not need to complete this list, but I believe that completing even just one or two of these items could be the saving grace of your presidency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;End military involvement in the Middle-East&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of your voters were voting for war. You promised to end the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, and while you may have done so on paper, we still have boots on the ground and dollars going out the door. It would be nice to stabilize the region, but we are $17,600,000,000,000 in debt. We can&amp;#39;t afford it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Close down the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guantanamo Bay is disgusting. The eagle is symbolic for the United States because we are supposed to soar, not stoop to the bottom. If we can not treat prisoners humanely, even under difficult circumstances, then we are no longer an honorable country. Please restore standards, ethics, and honor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Pardon Edward Snowden and Chelsea Manning&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You promised a transparent government and you failed to deliver. They only did what you said you would do; what the people voted for. They looked above the law, and did what was right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Reign in the NSA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The constant warrantless surveillence of the American people is a disgrace. You promised us that you would end the warrantless wire-tapping that was discovered under the Bush administration, but instead you have expanded it. Do you understand the difference between tyranny and liberty?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Protect Net Neutrality&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ISPs basically have a government granted monopoly, they don&amp;#39;t need more control over the Internet. Either break up the monopoly and force them to compete, or draft legislation that protects net neutrality. Growth in the technology sector is not something this country can afford to lose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please do not make excuses. George W. Bush&amp;#39;s regime could have made any of this happen. I don&amp;#39;t think you have what it takes to stand up and push through legislation that you believe in. Stop playing politics and start working on making this country better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jordan H. Braun&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>There is No Secret</title>
   <link href="http://jordanhbraun.github.io//2014/05/11/There-is-No-Secret/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://jordanhbraun.github.io/2014/05/11/There-is-No-Secret</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tips for success, lifehacks, habits of successful people... it&amp;#39;s all bullshit, and everyone should stop wasting their time reading and writing those articles. There is no secret sauce for effectiveness, success, or productivity. This may come as a shock to many, but it all comes down to hard work. Having a hard time focusing? You just need to try harder. Want to get twice as much done? Work twice as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many articles can possibly be written about getting enough sleep, exercising, and eating healthy? Why are people consuming this? I have a sneaking suspicion that it all comes down to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ergophobia&quot;&gt;ergophobia&lt;/a&gt;. Most people aren&amp;#39;t hard workers. The startup community is plagued with talkers and brainstormers. Reading articles about working feels like working, but it&amp;#39;s not. Only working is working. So here&amp;#39;s my one tip for success: Work harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work longer hours, get up earlier, go out less, do whatever it takes. Your dad was right when he went on rants about elbow grease and gumption. Hard work pays off. Elon Musk and Richard Branson aren&amp;#39;t sitting around reading dumbass articles on Buzzfeed and Lifehacker... they&amp;#39;re working, they&amp;#39;re crushing it, they know that there is no secret sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Organizing UX Knowledge with Trello</title>
   <link href="http://jordanhbraun.github.io//2014/02/21/Organizing-UX-Knowledge-With-Trello/"/>
   <updated>2014-02-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://jordanhbraun.github.io/2014/02/21/Organizing-UX-Knowledge-With-Trello</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The design process can be messy and chaotic. I&amp;#39;m a fan of any tool or procedure that helps me clean up and focus my workflow. I use a method of organizing knowledge in UX projects that I find to be simple and valuable, especially when working collaboratively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I try to get everyone involved in the project thinking in terms of unknowns, assumptions, and facts. Just doing this does wonders for communication, planning, and prioritization. Our goal will be to turn unknowns into assumptions, then into facts. I find &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trello.com&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; to be the perfect tool for organizing and manipulating this information. I create 3 lists: Unknowns, Assumptions, and Facts. Then I create cards in each list for pieces information relevant to the project.
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unknowns:&lt;/strong&gt; We don&amp;#39;t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User behaviors that we don&amp;#39;t understand and questions that we have about the problem we&amp;#39;re solving.
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assumptions:&lt;/strong&gt; We think we know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assumptions and predictions that we have made about the user. They are usually related to the user&amp;#39;s motivations or how the user will interact with the product.
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facts:&lt;/strong&gt; We know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way to make it on to this list is through testing, no excuses. Scientific facts are permitted, but common social assumptions should be tested and validated.
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bringing it all home&lt;/strong&gt;
Cards can be moved from unknowns to assumptions to facts through observation, testing, and validation. Follow the scientific method (&lt;em&gt;See post:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jhbraun.com/2014/11/20/Design-Science/&quot;&gt;Design Science: Testing is the process&lt;/a&gt;.) Unknowns should be observed and hypotheses (assumptions) should be formed. Assumptions should be tested and either turned into facts or back into unknowns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trello has great iOS, Android, and Windows 8 apps. Collaboration is easy. Modifying cards and dragging them from list to list is simple. You can make comments on cards and attach files. It&amp;#39;s everything that I love about white boards and post-it notes, but digital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Disclaimer: I currently have no affiliation with Trello, but we would love for that to change.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fuck the Guy Who Designed the Snooze Button</title>
   <link href="http://jordanhbraun.github.io//2014/02/14/Fuck-the-Guy-Who-Designed-the-Snooze-Button/"/>
   <updated>2014-02-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://jordanhbraun.github.io/2014/02/14/Fuck-the-Guy-Who-Designed-the-Snooze-Button</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;I took control of my life today.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been struggling, of and on, with the snooze button for as long as I can remember. My old man calls it a self-inflicted torture device. He’s right, but still I snoozed... until today. I’ve tried all sorts of schemes to beat the habit. I’ve left myself mean notes and taped them to the snooze button. I’ve moved the alarm away from my bed. I’ve tried making myself do jumping jacks when I get out of bed. But I could never fully quit the snooze. Today I took control. I decided not to fight the button any more, I killed it forever. I took apart my alarm clock and ripped that fucker out. No more snoozing. It never should have been part of the clock in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Design ethics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often think about my social responsibilities as a designer. A good design decision can carry a lot of weight. We are manipulators, psychologists, and social engineers. A big part of our job is to understand motivations and turn those motivations into behaviors. That’s a big responsibility, and I think we should quit taking it so lightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook notifications, Netflix autoplay, the snooze button... I’m opting out. I’m opting out of using them. I’m opting of designing them. These features are designed to manipulate our behaviors at our weakest moments. When we crave social interaction, when we’re having a hard time getting motivated, when we are too tired to turn down 10 more minutes of sleep. I want to use products that serve me and make me better. I was to design products the enable people, not distract them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding how to manipulate motivations in order to create behaviors can be a great thing. As designers, we can make people go to the gym, stay focused, spend more time with their kids, save more money... we can do anything! Let’s create experiences that push people to be better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
