<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jhbraun</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://www.jhbraun.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.jhbraun.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 02:30:07 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 02:30:07 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Privacy in Smart Cities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Smart Cities” mostly means “Smart Governments”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech and local governments are very gung-ho about “smart cities” right now. The basic concepts that add up to a smart city are connectivity, open data, and sensor-driven intelligence/automation. All of these things excite us in the tech industry, and government officials are finally starting to get on board. I have been to several smart cities oriented conferences and have seen a lot of great talks. One thing that isn’t being discussed enough is privacy. Are we building Big Brother?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of talk about the technology and infrastructure, and a lot of talk about the use cases. This is the fun stuff. We need to talk about the hard stuff. Are we building the foundation for an oppressive system? Are citizens willing to trade their data for these proposed benefits? The biggest question I have that isn’t being answered is: are we building these systems to empower citizens or to empower governments? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a post-Snowden world, these are the important questions. If smart cities are for smart citizens, we need to include citizens in the conversation, and actually listen to their concerns… and there are plenty of concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how you feel about the Snowden leaks, you would have to admit that they were shocking. Historically, we have enjoyed a certain level of transparency in our justice system. We don’t expect our government to spy on us without probable cause. We have warrants and privacy rights. Two years ago, talking about Big Brother in the Land of the Free earned you a title of “Conspiracy Theorist.” Now there is no denying that there is some level of mass surveillance going on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would argue that there would have been considerably less backlash against the NSA if the public had been aware of their practices. There could have been useful discourse around the constitutionality and effectiveness of surveillance. Even though a vast majority of citizens would not directly participate in any sort of debate, it is comforting to know that decisions are not being made behind closed doors. If things are done in the open. Even if a citizen doesn’t plan on going to bat for themselves, they should know that someone potentially could. Privacy advocates need to know what is going on, so that all of us can be protected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, any sort of data collection in public spaces needs to be done transparently. We need to decide what is and isn’t appropriate together as a community. In some cases, it might be enough for the debate to happen in government offices. In other cases there needs to be clear and visible warnings about what kind of collection is going on; especially when someone’s anonymity can be at stake. I see creating simple and legible signage for sensors in public spaces as one of the biggest design challenges for the Internet of Things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most citizens know intuitively when security is appropriate and when it is oppressive. We can mostly agree that metal detectors make sense at a courthouse and not a in a public park. Data privacy is no different. I realize that an airport might track my movements through their facilities, but I’m not necessarily comfortable with my city tracking my movements on their streets. This means that broad sweeping laws might not make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The context in which the data will be used is also important. Anonymized collection and analysis of traffic data for the sake of retiming red light cameras and adjusting speed limits is very different from analyzing the driving patterns of individuals. Part of transparency is being clear and honest about intended use. “We are collecting traffic data” is not enough. We deserve to know the difference between “We are collecting anonymized traffic data to improve traffic flow” and “We are collecting data to implicate criminals” because those things are very different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology has left consent behind. Our current efforts, such as Terms of Service, are fundamentally broken. If no one knows what they are agreeing to, how can you honestly call that consent? Terms of Service will continue to break down as technology moves away from personal devices and towards public infrastructure. We will see graphical user interfaces take a back seat to automation. This means even less opportunities to present users with information. This is another great design challenge for the Internet of Things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, we should be setting our own terms. We own our data, and we should be able to tell services what they are allowed to do with it. Currently, services tell us what they are going to do with it, and that’s only if we’re lucky. Often, data collection happens with zero permission and zero consent. This is the equivalent of “Well, she didn’t say ‘no’” counting as sexual consent. It’s ridiculous, it’s not good enough, and we should never accept that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Options&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citizens deserve options when they are uncomfortable with data collection, especially when dealing with public resources. If I don’t like Facebook’s privacy policy, I can delete my account. The lines get blurrier when we’re talking about public transit, parks, and sidewalks. Citizen’s shouldn’t have to opt-out of using their own resources. We should be able to choose to only share our data if it is anonymized, or if it is going to open data projects, or choose to opt out entirely. If data collection is being done in such a way that does not allow for options or an opt-out, maybe we should be questioning that method of data collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calling All Privacy Advocates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things for cities is a real thing. Sensors are being installed constantly and more and more data is being collected. Technology is moving fast than legislation and public discourse. Trying to stop the progress is most likely futile, but we can certainly influence how and when these solutions are implemented. Traditionally, designers have been advocates for the user. We need to become advocates for citizens now. Designers should be working hand in hand with citizens policy makers, lawyers, and engineers to ensure that privacy is valued in smart cities. Governments should not be acting as if these resources are theirs. The streets, parks, and sidewalks of our cities belong to us, the citizens. It is the government’s job to manage and maintain them. That does not give them the right to surveil and collect without any oversight or permission from its citizens. Smart cities are great, but the end goal should be smart citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jhbraun.com/2015/06/22/Privacy-in-Smart-Cities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jhbraun.com/2015/06/22/Privacy-in-Smart-Cities.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I Won&#39;t Design Without Testing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I am contracted, it is because I am needed as a design expert. No one is hiring me to make my best guess; they are hiring me to apply the design process to their problem. They might not know that; they might not even know what the design process is. That’s OK, I don’t know what the accounting process is, but I am sure my accountant follows it.That’s what an expert is. An expert is someone who can effective apply their craft. Shooting from the hip, or “just having an eye for it,” is not an expertise. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing is a crucial part of the design process. If you’re not testing, you’re guessing. I don’t feel comfortable guessing when people are paying me money to solve their problems. Even if I client requests that I skip research, prototyping, and testing, I can’t make my self do it. They don’t understand the design process, that is why they are contracting a designer. I can’t do my job effectively without testing, and I refuse to do my job poorly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I view design as the science of problem solving, so it seems logical to use the scientific method to solve design problems. The most effective way for me to explain the importance of research, prototyping, and testing in the design process is to show what the design process looks like with and without it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width:50%; float:left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientific Method&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;hr class=&quot;small&quot; /&gt;	
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Observe&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Hypothesize&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Experiment&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Analyze&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Conclude&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width:50%; float:left&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bullshit Method&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;hr class=&quot;small&quot; /&gt;	
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Hypothesize&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Conclude&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bullshit Method is not a problem solving framework, it’s the same framework people use to pick numbers for the lotto. Guessing is not effective. Adding white boards, post it notes, and wireframes into the mix doesn’t mean you’re not guessing. Testing is the answer. Test early, test often, test with users, test lo-fi, test high-fi, never stop testing. You will find the right answers with the scientific method. It cured polio and has helped us understand quantum physics, it is a good methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have had many clients ask me to skip straight to UI design with no research or testing, and I just can’t do it. I need my tools to do my job. I work with a lot of startups, and I know that time and money are both in short supply. Testing is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; something that you should skip to speed up the process. Reduce scope. Scope reduction is the only way to effectively save time and money without hurting quality. Removing testing from your process to save time is like throwing the bucket overboard to save a sinking ship. Throw some treasure overboard, not the one thing that can save you.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jhbraun.com/2014/12/23/Why-I-Wont-Design-Without-Testing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jhbraun.com/2014/12/23/Why-I-Wont-Design-Without-Testing.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design Science</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are designers, not artists.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we want to be great designers we need to start behaving more like scientists and less like artists. Design is not applied art; design is the science of problem solving. This is not an expression of our own thoughts, we are creating real solutions for real people.We are trying to solve problems for real people. We are not working in a closed studio in anticipation of a gallery opening. Testing isn’t part of the process; testing is the process. We need to be design scientists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientists know what’s up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a lot of lessons to learn from scientists. Their process and their mindset suits our goals well. Their process is continuous and cyclical, just like that word that we like to throw around: iterative. They embrace failure. This is just a buzz phrase in the design and startup world, but its reality for scientists. In the world of science, failure is every bit as important as success, as long as learning is happening. Scientists don’t design experiments stacked to succeed, they design experiments to isolate variables and learn. I’ve seen plenty of user tests designed to prove the hypotheses, this is bad design. Validation needs to go both ways, or you’re just wasting time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we want to be design scientists, and we acknowledge that testing is our process, then what does that process look like? The scientific method, of course!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part is up to you. Get out there and observe some people. Evaluate your product. Do some daydreaming. Discover your design problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypothesis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brainstorm your heart out. This is the fun part. A lot of people make the mistake of stopping here, or going straight to build after brainstorming. These are assumptions that need validated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build whatever you need to build and put it in front of people! Don’t build more than you have to, we just want to validate our assumptions as quickly as possible, so that we can make another run through this cycle. Keep your build focused on the test. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s time to evaluate what you’ve learned. Did the experiment hit its success criteria? Why or why not? New questions should be arising, which leads us back to our first step: the formulation of a question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing takes you where you need to be&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole process is the test. It is a cycle of learning and constant improvement. It is not something you do before or after a build. The build is something you do to support the test that leads us closer to our goal: better solutions. If you’re just testing at the beginning or the end of a build then your process is not a science. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jhbraun.com/2014/11/20/Design-Science.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jhbraun.com/2014/11/20/Design-Science.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>There is No Secret</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tips for success, lifehacks, habits of successful people… it’s all bullshit, and everyone should stop wasting their time reading and writing those articles. There is no secret sauce for effectiveness, success, or productivity. This may come as a shock to many, but it all comes down to hard work. Having a hard time focusing? You just need to try harder. Want to get twice as much done? Work twice as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many articles can possibly be written about getting enough sleep, exercising, and eating healthy? Why are people consuming this? I have a sneaking suspicion that it all comes down to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ergophobia&quot;&gt;ergophobia&lt;/a&gt;. Most people aren’t hard workers. The startup community is plagued with talkers and brainstormers. Reading articles about working feels like working, but it’s not. Only working is working. So here’s my one tip for success: Work harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work longer hours, get up earlier, go out less, do whatever it takes. Your dad was right when he went on rants about elbow grease and gumption. Hard work pays off. Elon Musk and Richard Branson aren’t sitting around reading dumbass articles on Buzzfeed and Lifehacker… they’re working, they’re crushing it, they know that there is no secret sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jhbraun.com/2014/05/11/There-is-No-Secret.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jhbraun.com/2014/05/11/There-is-No-Secret.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Organizing UX Knowledge with Trello</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The design process can be messy and chaotic. I’m a fan of any tool or procedure that helps me clean up and focus my workflow. I use a method of organizing knowledge in UX projects that I find to be simple and valuable, especially when working collaboratively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I try to get everyone involved in the project thinking in terms of unknowns, assumptions, and facts. Just doing this does wonders for communication, planning, and prioritization. Our goal will be to turn unknowns into assumptions, then into facts. I find &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trello.com&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; to be the perfect tool for organizing and manipulating this information. I create 3 lists: Unknowns, Assumptions, and Facts. Then I create cards in each list for pieces information relevant to the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unknowns:&lt;/strong&gt; We don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User behaviors that we don’t understand and questions that we have about the problem we’re solving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assumptions:&lt;/strong&gt; We think we know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assumptions and predictions that we have made about the user. They are usually related to the user’s motivations or how the user will interact with the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facts:&lt;/strong&gt; We know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way to make it on to this list is through testing, no excuses. Scientific facts are permitted, but common social assumptions should be tested and validated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bringing it all home&lt;/strong&gt;
Cards can be moved from unknowns to assumptions to facts through observation, testing, and validation. Follow the scientific method (&lt;em&gt;See post:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jhbraun.com/2014/11/20/Design-Science/&quot;&gt;Design Science: Testing is the process&lt;/a&gt;.) Unknowns should be observed and hypotheses (assumptions) should be formed. Assumptions should be tested and either turned into facts or back into unknowns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trello has great iOS, Android, and Windows 8 apps. Collaboration is easy. Modifying cards and dragging them from list to list is simple. You can make comments on cards and attach files. It’s everything that I love about white boards and post-it notes, but digital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Disclaimer: I currently have no affiliation with Trello, but we would love for that to change.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jhbraun.com/2014/02/21/Organizing-UX-Knowledge-With-Trello.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jhbraun.com/2014/02/21/Organizing-UX-Knowledge-With-Trello.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fuck the Guy Who Designed the Snooze Button</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-took-control-of-my-life-today&quot;&gt;I took control of my life today.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been struggling, of and on, with the snooze button for as long as I can remember. My old man calls it a self-inflicted torture device. He’s right, but still I snoozed… until today. I’ve tried all sorts of schemes to beat the habit. I’ve left myself mean notes and taped them to the snooze button. I’ve moved the alarm away from my bed. I’ve tried making myself do jumping jacks when I get out of bed. But I could never fully quit the snooze. Today I took control. I decided not to fight the button any more, I killed it forever. I took apart my alarm clock and ripped that fucker out. No more snoozing. It never should have been part of the clock in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-ethics&quot;&gt;Design ethics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often think about my social responsibilities as a designer. A good design decision can carry a lot of weight. We are manipulators, psychologists, and social engineers. A big part of our job is to understand motivations and turn those motivations into behaviors. That’s a big responsibility, and I think we should quit taking it so lightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook notifications, Netflix autoplay, the snooze button… I’m opting out. I’m opting out of using them. I’m opting of designing them. These features are designed to manipulate our behaviors at our weakest moments. When we crave social interaction, when we’re having a hard time getting motivated, when we are too tired to turn down 10 more minutes of sleep. I want to use products that serve me and make me better. I was to design products the enable people, not distract them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding how to manipulate motivations in order to create behaviors can be a great thing. As designers, we can make people go to the gym, stay focused, spend more time with their kids, save more money… we can do anything! Let’s create experiences that push people to be better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jhbraun.com/2014/02/14/Fuck-the-Guy-Who-Designed-the-Snooze-Button.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jhbraun.com/2014/02/14/Fuck-the-Guy-Who-Designed-the-Snooze-Button.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
